Gael Greene Magazine Collection 1968-2008 MSS.392
Fales Library and Special Collections
Gael Greene Magazine Collection
1968-2014
Fales Library and Special Collections
Greene, Gael
MSS.392
12.09 Linear Feet (31 boxes)
Gael Greene is an American restaurant critic, author and novelist. Ms. Greene is a graduate of the University of Michigan and became New York magazine's restaurant critic in fall 1968. This collection contains copies of magazines, primarily New York Magazine, in which articles by Gael Greene appear.
Scope and Content
This collection contains copies of New York Magazine, Manhattan, and other magazines in which articles by Gael Greene appear. The magazines have been kept in their original housing and order.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically, and numbered at the box level. Scope and Content notes for each box of magazines list the articles by Greene that appear in each magazine within that box. This list was compiled by Greene herself.
Provenance
The collection was donated to NYU's Fales Library and Special Collections in 2014.
Biographical Note
Gael Greene (born December 22, 1933) is an American restaurant critic, author and novelist. Greene is a graduate of the University of Michigan, and became New York magazine's restaurant critic in 1968. The American edition of The Foodie Handbook credits Greene with being the first person to use the word "foodie".
Greene famously went to great lengths to conceal her identity from restaurateurs, reserving and using credit cards under other names, and wearing hats that covered her eyes in photographs, on television, and in public appearances. Her writing inspired and documented the city's growing interest in food and dining out.
For more than 30 years, she served as New York magazine's "Insatiable Critic" and then continued as a columnist until 2008, the magazine's 40th anniversary as well as her own. She was then fired. The coverage surrounding her dismissal seemingly sparked a revival of interest in Greene, leading to appearances as a judge on the TV show Top Chef Masters and international requests for interviews focused on her web site, Insatiable Critic.com.
In 1981 she co-founded Citymeals-on-Wheels, along with the teacher and food writer James Beard, to help fund weekend and holiday meals for homebound elderly people in New York City. She remains an active chair of the company's board, hosting an annual Power Lunch for Women. Greene has received numerous awards for her work with Citymeals and in 1992 was honored as Humanitarian of the Year by the James Beard Foundation. She is the winner of the International Association of Cooking Professionals' magazine writing award (2000) and a Silver Spoon from Food Arts magazine.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Food writing.; Food writers.; Food |v Periodicals.; Greene, Gael
- Series I: Magazines
  Scope and Content
  This series contains magazines, arranged chronologically, in which articles by Gael Greene appear.
  - November 11, 1968 - November 30, 1970, 1968-1970 (Box 1)
    -11/11/68. NYM, Vol 1 # 32 (The Ground Floor). "Paley's Preserve." P.62-63
    -11/25/68. NYM, Vol 1 #34 (La Cote Basque). "The Quintessential Soule Food." P.56-57
    -1/6/69. NYM, Vol 2 #1 "The Menu Rap and How To Beat It." (Quo Vadis; 21; The Colony; Le Pavillon; The Four Season; The forum of the 12 caesars) P.60-61
    -2/17/69. NYM, vol. 2 # 7(Gaugin Room, MOMA). "Currying Favor at Columbus Circle." P.64
    -3/3/69. NYM, vol 2 # 9 (La Galerie). "A Taste for Culture." P.60-61
    -4/7/69. NYM,vol. 2 #14 (Luna, Lombardi, Vincent's Clam Bar, Paolucci, Vesuvio, La Stella). "The Mafia Guide to Dining Out." P.59-61
    -5/5/69. NYM, vol. 2 # 18 "And Not A Drop to Drink." P.62
    -5/19/69. NYM, vol. 2 # 20 (La Caravelle). "Insult a la Carte." P.58-69
    -6/2/69. NYM, vol. 2 #22 (Piraeus My Love, Mykonos, Jimmy's Greek-American Restaurant, Molfeta, Paradise Inn, Bacchus) "Champions a la Grecque." P 62-63
    -7/14/69. NYM, vol 2 #28 (Peter Luger's Steak House, Gage & Tollner, Lundy's, Michel's Restaurant, Pete's, Bonaparte, Otero, Monte's) "Brooklyn: Come Hungry." P.60-61
    -7/21/69. NYM, vol. 2 #29 (La Seine). "The Risen Phoenix Builds Her Nest." P.62-63
    -8/11/69. NYM, vol 2 # 32 (Fountain Cafe, Tavern-on-the-Green, Zoo Cafeteria, Chauveron's, Brasserie). "Do Feed the Animals." P.62-63
    -8/25/69. NYM, vol 2 # 34 (Monblason, La Rive) "Two for the Road." P.64-65
    -9/22/69.NYM vol 2 # 34 (Cafe Chauveron). "Cafe Chauveron as Love Object." P.60-61
    -10/6/69. NYM vol 2 #40 (Chun Cha Fu) "Far East Banquet on the Upper West." P.66-67
    -10/27/69. NYM, vol 2 # 43 (Steak & Brew, Steak Pub). "Permissive Gluttony." P.79-80
    -11/10/69.NYM, vol 2 #45 (La Grenouille). "Playing the Celebrity Lunch Game." P.84-88
    -12/1/69. NYM, vol 2 #50 (The Library, The Cellar Restaurant). "Not So Quiet on the Western Front." P.79-80
    -12/22/69. NYM, vol 2 # 51 (Cafe Chauveron, Four Seasons) "Haute-Meal for Pamela." P.78-81
    -1/12/70. NYM, Vol 3 # 2 (Four Seasons). "Can Spring be Far Behind?" P.63-65 (2)
    -1/26/70. NYM, vol 3 # 4 (Christ Cella, Pietro's, Sam's) "Carnivore's Carnival."P/65-66
    -2/9/70. NYM, vol 3 # 6 "A Beatitude of Brunch." P.58-61
    -2/16/70. NYM, vol 3 # 7 (Chez Vito, Executive Hotel, Charles') "The Food of Love --- Or Is It the Love of Food?" P.70-72
    -3/9/70. NYM, vol 3 # 10 (Burgers, etc.). (White Castle, McDonald's, Carrol's) "Grind House Glories.", P.64-65
    -3/23/70.NYM, vol 3 #12 (Lafayette) "Lafayette, We Are Leaving!" P.64-65
    -4/13/70. NYM, vol 3 #15 (La Madrigal, Lutece, Le Pavillon, La Seine, 21, La Grenouille, La Cote Basque, Colony, La Caravelle, LaFayette, Pearl's Chinese, Orsini's) "How Not To Be Humiliated in Snob Restaurants." P.33-35
    -4/27/70. NYM, vol 3 #17 (Lutece). "Miracle on 50th Street." P.72-73
    -5/11/70.NYM, vol 3 #19 (La Cremaillere, Coventry Forge Inn) "Two More for the Road." P.65-66
    -5/25/70. NYM, vol 3 # 21 (The Russian Tea Room). "An Indulgence of Sour Cream." P.72-73
    -7/6/70. NYM, vol 3 #27 "Resuscitation at a Price: Don't-Do-It-Yourself Picnic and Other Therapeutic Indulgences." P.42-47
    -7/20/70. NYM, vol 3 #29 (Sayat Nova, Cafe Europa, La Cocotte). "In-Town Alfresco." P.64-65
    -8/3/70. NYM, vol 3 #31 (Baskin-Robbins, Haagen-Dazs, Good Humor, Carvel, Yum Yum, Camel's Hump, The Ice Cream Connection, Health E Snack, Wil Wright's, The Flick, Hicks, Old-Fashioned Mr. Jennings, Trattoria, Rumpelmayer's, Ferrara's, Schrafft's, Capri Pizza, Serendipity's, Blum's, Jahn's, Mr. Waffles, Acropolis) "Everything You Always Wanted to Know About Ice Cream But Were Too Fat To Ask." P.42-47
    -8/17/70.NYM, vol 3 #33 (Le Madrigal). "Luncheon for Lovers." P56-57
    -8/31/70. NYM, vol 3 #35 (Adam's Rib, The Duck Joint). "The One-Track Mind." P.64-65
    -9/21/70.NYM vol 3 # 38 (Le Pavillion). "Excorcising the Ghost at Le Pavillion." P.64-65
    -10/5/70. NYM, vol 3 #40 (Bottled water) "How to Avid the Tap Trap." P.62-64
    -10/19/70. NYM, vol 3 #42 (Trader Vic's, Hawaii Kai, South Pacific Ports). "The Tiki Track." P.70-73
    -11/2/70. NYM, vol 3 #44 (The Forum, Charley O's, The Four Season, Zum Zum, The Tower Suite) "Twilight of the Gods." P.43-51
    -11/16/70. NYM, vol 3 #46 (Barbetta). "No Mere Truffle." P.78-80
    -11/30/70. NYM, vol 3 #48 "Ma Vie Avec Le Grape Nut." P.63
  - December 14, 1970 - November 20, 1972, 1970-1972 (Box 2)
    -12/14/70. NYM vol 3 #50 (Osini's). "The Princedom of Pasta." P.86-89
    -1/4/71. NYM, Vol 4, issue 1 (The Colony). "Colony Waxworks." P.61-63
    -1/18/71. NYM, Vol 4 issue3 (21). "The Graying of '21'". P.62-65
    -3/1/71. NYM,Vol.4 issue 9 (The bear) "The Bear of Woodstock" P.64-65
    -3/29/71. NYM, Vol. 4, issue 13, (Elaine's, Lou G. Siegel's). "It Must Be Calf's Foot Jelly Cause Canneloni Don't Shake Like That." (2) P.63-65
    -4/12/71. NYM, Vol 4, issue 15 (The Palm, Wally's, Old Homestead, Frankie & Johnnie's, Joe & Rose). "The Unabashed Carnivore." (2) 66-73
    -4/26/71. NYM Vol 4, issue 17, (Al Mounia). "The Couscous Complaint." P.80-81
    -5/10/71. NYM Vol 4, issue 19 (The GF and La Ferme). "Thaw at the Ground Floor, Chill at La Ferme." 79-81
    -5/17/71. NYM, Vol4, issue 20 "Confessions of a Sensualist." P.64-67
    -5/31/71. NYM Vol 4, issue 22, (Quo Vadis). " Quo Vadis, Edible Feelgood." P.63-64
    -6/21/71. NYM, Vol 4, issue 25, (Howard Johnson's, Luchow's, Riverboat, Patricia Murphy's Candlelight Restaurants, Trattoria, Top of the Sixes, Laurent, Hyde Park, Manero's, Nathan's, Steer Palace, Mamma Leone's Hawaii Kai, La Fonda del Sol, Red Coach Grill, The Autopub) "Into the Mouths of Babes." P.70-73
    -7/5/71. NYM, Vol 4, issue 27 (Eating for Lovers--Grant's Promenade Cafe, Barbetta, Rainbow Room, Under the Stairs, Victor's, Les Pyrenees, The Plaza, Orsini, Elaine's, 21, Waldorf, Commodore, Motel On the Mountain, Chateau Henri IV, Four Seasons, Ground Floor) "Where to Feed Summer Appetites." P.32-33
    -7/26/71. NYM Vol 4, issue 30 (Pearl's). "The Scrutable Ouch." P.57-58
    -8/16/71. NYM, Vol 4, issue 33 (Nicole Paone's, Mama Leone's). "Gluttony With Grandeur" P.64-65
    -9/13/71. NYM Vol4, issue 37 (Cooking Instruction). "The Haute Stove." P.75-77
    -9/20/71, NYM, Vol 4, issue 38, "The Haute Stove, Part Two" P.68-73
    -9/27/71. NYM Vol4, issue 39 (The House of Chan, Flower Drum, The Gourmet Chinese Kitchen Cooking School, Grace Chu, Shun Lee Dynasty). "High-Rent Chinese." P.66-70
    -10/25/71. NYM Vol 4, issue 43 (Miss Grimble). "A Cast of Torte." P.70
    -10/25/71.NYM, Vol.4 issue 43 (Stonehenge). "Shadows at Stonehenge." (2) p.76-78
    -11/22/71. NYM, Vol 4, issue 47 (The Spanish Pavillion, Toledo, Marbella Restaurant, Fornos). "The Paella Perplex." P.86-90
    -12/6/71. NYM, Vol4, issue 49 (Cookbook Reviews). "To Browse, Perchance to Baste." P.81-86
    -1/24/72. NYM Vol 5, issue 4 (Le Perigord Park, Cafe Argenteuil). "Comfort Me With Mousse Pralinee." P.70-71
    -3/20/72. NYM, Vol 5, issue 12 (Romeo Salta, Nanni's, La Trattoria del Pappagallo, San Marco, Aperitivo, Giambelli-50th, Trattoria da Alfredo, San Marino, Italian Pavilion, Giambelli, Casa Mario, Giovanni's, Nick & Guido's, Trattoria, Lino's U.N. Restaurant, Ballato). "Honor Thy Pasta." (2) P.36-44
    -4/17/72. NYM, Vol. 5, issue 16 (Lord & Taylor, Bergdorf Goodman, Bonwit, Bloomingdale, Altman, Alexander, Korvette, Gimbels East, Gimbels, Macy's, Abraham & Straus). "Fuel for the Passionate Shopper." P.90-94
    -5/15/72. NYM Vol 5, issue 20 (Le Cynge). "The Swanpond." (2) p.78-79
    -6/12/72. NYM, Vol 5, issue 24 (France: Le Pot au Feu, Hostellerie Moulin de Mougins, Aux Lyonnais, Au Pactole, Tour d'Argent, Chez Garin, Au Petit Montmorency, Lameloise, Pyramide, Oustau de Baumaniere, Hostellerie Moulin de Mougins). "Status Reports on La Grande Cuisine." (2) P.49-56
    -6/26/72. NYM, Vol. 5, issue 26 (France: Troisgros). "A Gourmanical Detour." P.59-61
    -7/31/72. NYM, Vol 5, issue 31 (S.S. France). "The S.S. France: Haute Afloat." P.56-59
    -9/25/72. NYM, Vol 5, issue 39, "The Kitchen as Errogenous Zone." P.35-39
    -10/23/72. NYM Vol. 5, issue 43 (Box). "Bacchic Bon Mots." P.72
    -10/30/72. NYM, Vol 5, issue (Le Pavillon) "The Inevitable Adieu." P.81-85
    -11/20/72. NYM, Vol 5, issue 47 (Jimmy's) "Recipe for a Political Restaurant." (2) P.94-96
  - December 18, 1972 - December 23, 1974, 1972-1974 (Box 3)
    -12/18/72. NYM, Vol 5, issue 51, "The Contentment of Cookbooks." P.120-126
    -1/22/73. NYM,Vol 6, issue 4 (Rainbow Room). "The High and the Flighty." P.66-69
    -2/5/73.NYM, Vol6, issue 6 Paul Bocuse Cooks the Dinner of the Century "Trial by Pig's Bladder." P.76-81
    -4/2/73.NYM, Vol, 6, issue 14 (Brussels, Caliban). "Two Grapey Obessions." P.73-76
    -4/30/73.NYM, Vol6, issue 18 "The Decadent Delights of Breakfast in Bed." P.59-63
    -5/28/73.NYM, Vol.6, issue 22 (France: Chez La Mere, Restaurant Bourgeois ). "A Mouthful of Stars."P.78-83
    -6/11/73.NYM, vol 6, issue 24 (Italy: Al Cantunzein, Ristorante Fini, 12 Apostoli, Trattoria Cantarelli, Locanda dell' Isola Comacina, Antico Albergo e Ristorante Rocca). "Honor Thy Pasta...In Italy." P.86-88
    -7/9/73.NYM, Vol 6, issue 28, (Tik Tak). "The Paprika Persuasion." P.72-73
    -9/17/73. NYM, vol 6, issue 38 (Lutece, Romeo Salta, Russian Tea Room, Cafe Argenteuil, Hunam, Carnegie Deli, The Coach House) "Greatest Dishes in Town." (2) p.54-56
    -10/1/73. NYM, Vol 6, issue 40 (Hunam, Uncle Tai's Hunan Yuan, David Keh's Chinese Seafood House, Shun Lee Palace, Szechuan East). "Star Struck at Hunan. " p.85-90
    -10/22/73.. NYM Vol.6, issue 43, "The Care and Feeding of Friends: How New Yorkers Entertain."P.49-52
    -11/l2/73.NYM, Vol.6, issue46 (France:Les Freres Troisgros, Pot-au-Feu, Restaurant Barrier, Cafe de Paris, Hostellerie du Moulin de Mougins, Restaurant Le Duc, Reginskaia). "Nodody Knows the Truffles I've Seen." p.94-103
    -1/21/74. NYM, Vol 7, issue 3, (European Spas). "They Also Serve Who Only Watch Your Weight." (2) P.65-67
    -1/28/74. NYM, Vol.7, issue 4, "More Confessions of a Sensulist."p. 70-72
    -2/18/74. NYM, Vol. 7, issue 7 (The Coach House). "The Coach House is Bullish on America." P.84
    -5/20/74. NYM, Vol.7 issue 20, (Gertrude's). "Chic to Chic At Gertrude's." (2) P.106-108
    -6/10/74. NYM, Vol 7, issue 23, (Paris: Chez Rene, L'Orangerie). "Gael Among the Bries." P.82-83
    -6/17/74. NYM, Vol7, issue 24 (Paris: Restaurant Cartet, Lous Landes). "Losing My Head at Marie-Antoinette's." p.90-93
    -6/24/74. NYM, Vol 7, isue 25 (Paris: Le Duc, Le Pactole). "Paris is My Oyster." P.70-72
    -7/8/74. NYM, Vol 7, issue 27 (France: fast food). "Le Big Mac Alors." P.76-78
    -7/15/74. NYM, Vol 7, issue 28 (Southern France: Tetou). "La Vie en Bleu." P.54-56
    -10/28/74. NYM, Vol. 7, issue 43, "Feastability Study, Five Enchanted Evenings." P.53-57
    -11/4/74. NYM, Vol.7, issue 44, "Through the Cooking Class."P.80
    -11/4/74. NYM, Vol. 7, issue 44 (La Rotisserie, Tre Amici, Monk's Court, Horn of Plenty, Adams Rib, Duck Joint). "Love is Hungrier the Second Time Around."P.103-108
    -12/2/74. NYM, Vol 7, issue 48 (Les Pres et les Source d'Eugenie, l'Hotel-Residence du Bois). "I Lost it At the Baths."P.93-99
    -12/23/74. NYM, Vol. 7 (Shopping). "Christmas Excess." P.53-55
  - Februaury 10, 1975 - June 6, 1977, 1975-1977 (Box 4)
    -2/10/75. NYM, Vol 8, issue 6, (Akron; Sloans, Bonte Patisserie, Marcella, Rosedale, Trentacosta, Bazaar) "The $10 Challenge: Feasting on the Cheap." P.30-37
    -3/3/75 NYM. Vol. 8 issue 9. Vol 8 (Lutece, La Caravelle, Cafe Argenteuil, La Cote Basque, La Grenouille, Le Cygne, Le Madrigal, Quo Vadis, Le Mistral, Lafayette, La Petite Ferme, La Goulue, Le Cirque, Le Veau d'Or, Laurent, Le Perigord Park). "Re-evaluating Manhattan's Top Ten Restaurants."P.38-50
    -4/28/75. NYM, Vol 8, issue 17 (The Palace). "How They Ate in Pompeii Before the Lava Flowed." P.111-113
    -5/26/75. NYM, vol.8, issue 21 (The Box Tree, Gavroche, Il Valletto). "Please Don't Eat the Calla Lillies." P.79-82
    -7/7/75. NYM, Vol8, No.27 (Shun Lee Palace, EAT, Loaves & Fishes, Alfredo, The Oyster Bar, Mr. Babbington & Friend, La Rotisserie, Francaise) "Splendor on the Grass: My Dream Picnics."P.54-57
    -7/14/75. NYM, Vol 8, No. 28 (Squires, Moveable Feast, Shazam, The Hedges, Spring Close House, Lobster Inn, American Hotel, Fat Flounder). " Hamptons Dining: A Pluperfect Day for Bananafish."P.54-59
    -7/21/75. NYM, Vol 8, No. 29 "Kitchen Bouquet."P.61
    -7/21/75. NYM, Vol 8, No. 29(The Pizza Place Next to Jackie Rogers, Gosman's, Silver's Cigar Store, Lobster Roll, Loaves and Fishes, The Store in Amagansett). "Fast Food for the Summer Sloth."P.66-67
    -5/28/75 NYM
    -8/18/75. NYM, Vol 8, No. 33 (Elaine's, Nicola's). "It's Not Nice to Fool Mother Kaufman."P.53-55
    -11/3/75. NYM, Vol 8, No. 44 (Le Colisee The Four Seasons). Le Colisee Thrown to the Lions." P.101-105
    -11/17/75. NYM, Vol.8, No.46 (Special Section on Connoisseurship). "Gael Greene Entertains With Diet Recipes of France's Most Creative Chef."P.84-89
    -1/19/76. NYM, Vol 9, No. 3 (Cafe des Artistes). "The Cafe des Artistes: If It's Good Enough for George."P.70-74
    -4/5/76. NYM, Vol. 9, No. 14 (The Palace). "Splendour in the Foie Gras."P.86
    -5/3/76. NYM, Vol.9, No.18 (Ernie's, La Bourgogne, L'Etoile). "California Sweet." P 83-91
    -5/10/76. NYM, Vol. 9, No. 19 (Regine's). "Full House for the Queen of Clubs." P.36-39
    -5/10/76 NYM. New West. "California Sweet," Pg. 101.
    -6/21/76. NYM, Vo.9, No. 25 (The Belmore). "Meter and Potatoes." P.42
    -7/19/76. NYM, Vol.9, No.29 "Party Fare."P.44-45
    -9/20/76.NYM, Vol.9, No.38 (Les Pits). "Amateur Night at Les Pits." 100-101
    -9/27/76NYM, Vol.9, No.39 "The Sensuous Hors d'Oeuvre."( Evan/Judith Jones, Stanley Landsman, Cecilia Yen Woo, The Batterberrys. P.49-52
    -10/11/76.NYM (New West), Vol. 1, No. 13 "The Happy Cooking School In Napa."P.149-150
    -12/13/76. NYM, Vol.9, No.50 "British Chefs Take Over Maxims...But How Could They Presume.?" P.119-120
    -1/31/77. NYM, Vol.10, No.5 Vol 10 (Le Cirque). "I Love Le Cirque, But Can I Be Trusted?"P62-65
    -4/25/77. NYM, Vol10, No.17(The Cellar in the Sky). "1 Rm, No Riv Vu."P68
    -5/9/77. NYM, Vol.10, No.19 (The Palace). "In Praise of the High-Wire Act at The Palace. P.64
    -5/16/77. NYM, Vol10, No.20 (Box Tree Inn). "Wonderfully Preposterous Luxury at the Box Tree Inn."P75-77
    -5/23/77. NYM, Vol.10, No.21, Special Food & Wine Issue: "Ceremony of Indolence: The Haute Covered-Dish Supper." p.37-39
    -6/6/77.NYM, Vol10, issue 23, Speacial 12-Page Handbook (Victor's café; The red Baron; Museum Café; Genghiz's Bicycle; Taco Villa; Café du Centre; Ruskay's Restaurant; Parentheses; Dobson's; Monastery): Columbus Avenue--Rebirth of a Vibrant Street. Dining Out" P.50-53.
  - July 18, 1977 - April 14, 1980, 1977-1980 (Box 5)
    -7/18/77. NYM, Vol 10, issue 29, Insatiable Critic (The Quilted Girafe, New Paltz) "A Celebration of Amateurs."p.64-65 1975 in new paltz. 79
    -10/3/77.NYM, Vol.10, issue 40 (Regine's). "Feeding the Night Crawler."p.60-62
    -10/17/77. NYM, Vol 10, issue 42 (France: Alain Chapel, Les Freres Troisgros, Paul Bocuse, L'Auberge de l'Ill, Le Relais a Mougins, L'Amandier de Mougins, Le Duc, L'Archestrate, Tailevent, Jacques Cagna, Gerard Pangaud). "Stalking the Moveable Feast."p.47-57
    -1/30/78.NYM,Vol 11,no.5 "Murder In The Kitchen". P46-48
    -6/5/78. NYM, Vol 11, no 23, Special: Food-Wine: "Breaking the Rules." P.44-48
    -7/24/78. NYM, Vol 11, no 30 "Pie in the Sky."(TWA) P.52-53
    -7/24/78. NYM, Vol 11, no 30 "Best Bite Better Than a Cookie."p.60
    -9/25/78. NYM, Vol11, no.39 "Gael Greene on Wonderous Market" P.120
    -10/9/78.NYM, Vol11, no.41 (Restaurant Raphael, Le Lavandou, Le Chantilly, La Folie). "Some Like it Haute." p.76-81
    -12/18/78.NYM, Vol.11, issue 51 (The Palm, Peter Luger, Sparks, Christ Cella, Gallagher's, Pietro's, U.S. Steakhouse, Pen & Pencil, Broadway Joe, Smith & Wolensky). "Prime Time: The Best Steak in Town."P.67-77
    -1/22/79. NYM, Vol.12, no.4 (Claude's). "Claude Reigns." P.68-72
    -3/12/79. NYM, VOL 12, ISSUE 11 (Sylvia's). "Harlem on My Mind."P.62-63
    -4/2/79. NYM, VOL 12, ISSUE 14, (Shun Lee Palace, Fortune Garden, HSF, David K's, Uncle Tai's Hunan Yuan, Hunam, Pearl's, Gold Coin, Peking Park, Flower Drum, Peng's, House of Chan, The Dumpling House, Tung, Sing, Hee Seung Fung, Canton, Hop Shing, Hoolok Corporation, Phoenix Garden, Say Eng Look, Szechuan Taste, Lam Kee, China Royal, No. 1 Chinese Restaurant, Hunan Garden, Foo Joy). "A Scrutable Guide to New York's Chinese Restaurants." P.43 -58 (3)
    -5/28/79.NYM,VOL.12, ISSUE 22 Food & Wine: "Sunday, Delicious Sunday; the Abundant Joys of Sunday at Home."P.58-66
    -7/9-16/79. NYM, Vol.12, issue 28, Summer Pleasures: "Noodlecraft." P.47 "The Long Haute Summer." P.56 " Salad Days." P.57
    -7/9-16/79. NYM, Vol.12, issue 28 (Le Plaisir). "Pure Plaisir." P.81
    -8/13-20/79. NYM, Vol.12. no32, Tales of New York: "Conditions, Conditions." P.41-43
    -9/10/79. NYM, Vol. 12, issue 35 (Dodin-Bouffant). "Cuisine From a Marriage." P.62-64
    -9/24/79. NYM,Vol,12, issue 37 (Take Zushi). "The Joy of Sushi." P.84-86
    -12/17/79. NYM, Vol.12, no 49, (Claude's). "Claude's, the Second Time Around." P.103
    -12/31/79. NYM, Vol. 13, issue 1 "From Here To Eternity (Ten Years After)." P.58-59
    -12/31/79 NYM, Vol.13, issue 1, Year-End Issue. (Chanterelle). "The Daring Young Man on Grand Street." P.66-68 (2)
    -2/25/80. NYM, Vol13, issue 8 (Manhattan Market, Quilted Girafe). "Nouvelle Notions and Naivete." P.44-47
    -3/10/80.NYM, Vol.13, issue 10 (Dodin-Bouffant, The Palace, Lutece, Le Plaisir, The Four Seasons, Shun Lee Palace, Trattoria Da Alfredo, The Palm). "Eight Wondeful Dinners: The Sensualist at Table."P.39-42
    -3/24/80. NYM, Vol. 13, issue 12, "Jam Session; Rating the Strawberry Preserve." P.60-64
    -4/14/80. NYM, Vol13, issue 15 (La Cote Basque). "That Old Cote Basque Music."P64-68
  - May 12, 1980 - December 20, 1982, 1980-1982 (Box 6)
    -5/12/80.NYM, Vol 13, No.19 (La Gauloise). "An Almost Perfect Bistro."P.55
    -5/12/80, NYM, Vol 13, No.19, (The Palace) "Eat Drink and Be Mommy" P.56
    -5/19/80. NYM, Vol.13, No.20 ( La Tulipe). "La Tulipe in Bloom."P.66-87
    -6/2/80. NYM, Vol.13, No.22(Restaurant d'Olympe, Le Bernadin, Gerard Pangaud, Prunier-Madeleine, Le Duc, Le Marcande, Le Trou, Gascon, Hotel de France, Restaurant Vahel, La Table des Cordeliers, L'Aubergade, Restaurant Girardet, Clavel, La Tupina) "What's Nouvelle? La Cuisine Bourgeoise." P.32-40
    -6/23/80. NYM, Vol.13, No.25(Restaurant, Lesile, Uzies, Cafe 58, La Ripaille, Sammy's, Janice's Fish Place, San Martin, Le Veau d'Or, Adams Rib, Soom Thai, Madras Woodlands, Chateau Bahia, Bistro 79 West, Elaine's, Le Petit Robert, La Folie, Le Steak, Hunan Manor, Andree's Mediterranean Cuisine). "Eating Smart:Great Dinners for Two for $50." P.34-48
    -6/23/80. "Cod Comfort"
    -7/7-14/80.NYM, Vol13, No.27 (The Little Bear, La Rive, Bird & Bottle Inn, Culinary Institute of America, Wilford's) Summer Pleasures: "Country Dinners Worth the Drive."P.45-53
    -8/11/80. (NO) NYM, Vol. 13, No.31 (Crawdaddy, Duck Joint, La Rotisserie, Britany du Soir, Piro's, Hisae's, House of Taiwan, Captain's Table, El Sombrero, Raga). "Eat, Drink, and Be Wary."P.30-33
    -11/3/80. NYM, Vol.13.No.43 (Food & Wine Special Section). "Good For You!" "Dinner After the fact." "The Bachelor Improvises." (2) P.31-42
    -11/17/80. NYM, Vol.13.No.45 (Kurumazushi, Shalom Japan). "The Seaweed Factor." P.77-79
    -12/29/80-1/15/81.NYM, Vol. 14, No.1 "Hey, Good Lookin', What Ya Got Cookin'?" P.43-44
    -12/29/80-1/15/81 "Food Glorious Food"
    -1/12/81. NYM, Vol14, No.2 Winter Pleasures: "Swee'pea: Super to Go." Dinner on Your Doorstep; Sublime Sunday, by Phone"P.23
    -1/12/81. NYM. Vol14, No.2 (Le Plaisir, Dodin-Bouffant, Palace, Lutece, Quilted Giraffe, Chanterelle). Winter Pleasures: "Great Chefs, Inspired Feasts."18-20
    -1/81 NYM. Best of New York. "Eating Smart," p. 1-10.
    -2/23/81. NYM, Vol 14, No.8 (Helmsley Palace, Le Trianon, The Gold Room, Grand Hyatt, Sweet Trumpet's). "Delusion and Delight: The New Haute Hotels." P.32-35
    -4/13/81. NYM, Vol.14, No.15 (River Cafe). "Of Food and The River." P.60-61
    -5/18/81.NYM, Vol14, No.20, (Gurney's and Spa at Palm-Aire) "Taking It Off at the Super-Spas." P.34-38 (2)
    -5/18/81. NYM,Vol.14, No.20 "Truffles and Flourishes." P.61
    -6/22/81. NYM, Vol.14, No.25. (Little Afganistan, Pamir Restaurant). "An Afghan Detour." P.53-54
    -7/20/81.NYM, Vol.14, No.28, (Shun Lee West, Home Village Restaurant). "Chinese-Haute or Home-Style." (2) P.50-53
    -7/20/81. (NO)NYM, "Best Bites." P.57